we have polarization in politics a lot
of hate going on people are tense angry
we have viruses that are going around
has people nervous fearful we look at
the state of our society today and we've
got depression at an all-time high
people are dealing with sicknesses we're
dealing with mass shootings happening
all over the place even in churches
natural disasters earthquakes hurricanes
there's a lot going on and if we ever
needed the Lord it is now pray with me
please Heavenly Father speak to us for a
few moments as we open your word in
Jesus name we pray amen my message today
is really it's really simple it's a
simple it's a simple message I want to
give you advice today it's more than
advice because it's the Word of God amen
if I was giving you advice it would be
you could take it or leave it but this
is the word of God we're looking at and
it's his advice that I want to give you
this morning I want you to turn with me
to the book of Matthew chapter 24
Matthew chapter 24 and we're going to
read from verse 7 the Bible says for
nation shall rise against nation and
against Kingdom and there shall be
famines and pestilences and earthquakes
in diverse places do you see this
happening now everyone it goes on to say
all these are the beginning of Sorrows
then shall they deliver you up to be
afflicted and shall kill you and you
shall be hated for of all nations for my
name's sake
and then shall many be offended and
betray one another and shall hate one
another do you see this going on many
false prophets shall rise and shall
deceive many and because iniquity shall
abound the love of many shall wax cold
do you see this happening today the
Bible says but he that shall endure unto
the end the same shall be saved and then
verse 14 and this gospel of the kingdom
shall be preached in all the world for a
witness unto all nations and then shall
the end come let me rephrase these
verses that we just read to simply say
we're living in serious times
everybody is uptight
my advice we don't know how to lighten
up
yes we're living in serious times but I
just think that we ought to just lighten
up
I know it doesn't sound right right like
it's no time to take things lightly if
we're living in serious times but I
believe that if we just lighten up even
just a little why should we lighten up
in a time when things are so seriously
so serious the book of Ephesians chapter
6 verse 12 the Bible tells us therefore
we wrestle not against flesh and blood
but against principalities against
powers against the rulers of what the
darkness of this world against spiritual
wickedness in high places beloved the
world is becoming a dark place and
because of that we need to lighten up I
don't know if you're catching me so
let's go back and read that text in
Isaiah chapter 60 verses one through
three
it was our scripture reading for the day
Isaiah 60 verse 1 through 3 the Bible
says arise and lighten up arise and
lighten up arise and shine for thy light
has come and the glory of the Lord is
risen upon the verse 2 for behold what
the darkness shall cover the earth and
gross darkness the people but the Lord
shall arise upon thee and his Watts
glory shall be seen upon the verse 3 and
the Gentile shall come to thy Watts
light and Kings to the brightness of thy
rising god encourages us hey I know
things are dark
I know things are hard but trust me I
just need you to what everyone lighten
up how many of you would like to lighten
up yeah just a little bit if we could
just lighten up just a little bit you
know the Bible says a merry heart doeth
good like a medicine well what is it
that makes us merry it's the gospel
Jesus says lighten up the world needs it
the world is a dark place and they
needed beloved what I'm telling you is
prophetic just go with me to Revelation
chapter 18 verse 1 in Revelation 18
verse 1 the Bible says after these
things I saw another angel coming down
from heaven having great power and the
earth was what the earth was what
lightened with his glory beloved does
the earth need lightening up absolutely
and this angel in Revelation 18 1 is
symbolic of a message but a message
cannot be given without messengers
meaning God is calling his people - one
more time everyone lighten up
why because the world needs it and if we
don't know how to lighten up
we are only adding to the darkness of
this world you need to know how to
lighten up how many of you would like to
know how to lighten up this morning I'm
gonna give you seven ways to lighten up
7 ways to help you lighten up number one
second corinthians chapter four and
verse three second corinthians chapter
four verse 3 but if our gospel be hid it
is hid to them that are lost in whom the
god of this world has blinded the minds
of them which believe not lest the Watts
light of the glorious gospel of Christ
who is the image of God should shine
unto them
for we preach not ourselves but Christ
Jesus the Lord and ourselves your
servants for Jesus sake
let's read this one again
for God who commanded the watt light to
shine out of what darkness has shined in
our hearts to give the watt light of the
knowledge of the glory of God in the
face of Jesus Christ beloved when you
understand salvation when you have
salvation the light of the glory of the
knowledge of God it ought to make you
lighten up it ought to make you lighten
up Colossians chapter 1 verse 27 the
Bible says to whom god would make known
what is the riches of the glory of this
mystery among the gentiles which is
christ in you the hope of glory why do
we lighten up if salvation is in us
because Christ is in us and Christ is
the light of the world
if salvation is in if you understand
salvation you will be able to live
lightened up you will be able to look at
this dark world and not allow the
darkness to depress you to overwhelm you
you will have let me say this way power
to lighten up how many of you would like
tower to lighten up beloved the glory
the Christ in you is the hope of glory
and it's very interesting because if you
look at Revelation chapter 14 verse 6
and 7 the Bible says that God's people
at the end of time are to go forth with
a message which says fear God and what
give glory when your giving glory what
are you giving you're giving what light
because light is God's glory so check
the sagas you cannot give the first
angels message if you don't have it you
can't give God glory if you don't have
glory to give did you catch that just
now
you cannot fulfill the first angels
message give glory to God if you don't
you can't give what you don't have so in
order to give glory to God in order to
give glory to God in the midst of
coronavirus and in the midst of of mass
shootings and in the midst of calamities
and in the midst of of a world that
seems to be growing darker and darker by
the day by the minute in order to give
glory to God you have to have glory in
you and the only way to have glory in
you is to have Christ the hope of glory
in you so just lighten up lighten up let
that light be seen on your face lighten
up number two number two the second way
to lighten the Romans chapter 13 verse
11 Romans chapter 13 verse 11 the Bible
says and that knowing the time that now
it is high time to awake out of sleep
for now is our salvation nearer than
when we believed the night is far spent
the day is at hand let us therefore cast
off the works of darkness and let us put
on the armor of what lights
let us not walk or let us walk honestly
as in the day not in rioting and
drunkenness not in chambering and
wantonness not in strife and envying but
put you on the Lord Jesus Christ and
make not provision for the flesh to
fulfill the lusts thereof beloved the
second way to love is to lighten up by
putting on the armor of light amen
the armor of light beloved allows us to
defeat the lusts of the flesh how many
of you remember what happened in the
book of Acts chapter 2 what happened in
Acts chapter two come on church what
happened in Acts chapter two the
outpouring of the holy spirit were the
disciples lightened up absolutely they
were enlightened up because they Lord
the Spirit of God fell on them and the
Bible tells us in Galatians chapter
five and verse six that we ought to walk
in the I'm sorry not verse six verse
sixteen Galatians chapter five verse 16
this I say then walk in the wot spirit
and you shall not fulfill the lust of
the flesh beloved if you walk in the
spirit you are going to walk lightened
up in fact in fact the book of Psalm 37
verse 6 notice what it says here he
shall bring forth thy righteousness as
the walks as the what as the light and
thy judgment as the noonday when the
Spirit of God is dwelling in you you
know how to lighten up you know how to
walk in light and people will see you
and and notice that there is something
different about you in other words you
know how to lighten up because the
Spirit of God is dwelling in you the
third way to lighten up is salt is found
in psalm 119:105 turn there with me if
you will or it should be up on a screen
the Bible says thy word is a want lamp
unto my feet and a light unto my path
beloved you and I have the word of God
Amen if you want to lighten up if you
want to lighten up take heed to the Word
of God but I mean the Word of God is
like an anchor it is a light in a dark
place and so God says listen we are
living in a world where people now don't
believe anything to be true everything
is a conspiracy oh if you don't like it
it's fake news man you're just guys
lighten up please all right so mad there
is one thing that is sure and certain
and it is the Word of God Jesus gives us
this word so that
we can lighten up we can live in truth
in a world of darkness in a world of
error not only beloved does the word of
God allow us to lighten up because it is
truth but we're told in 2nd Peter
chapter 119 we have also a more sure
word of what prophecy where until you do
well that you take heed as unto a light
that shines in a dark place until the
day dawn and the day star arise in your
hearts what am I saying prophesy beloved
allows us to lighten up beloved when we
understand the books of Daniel the book
of Revelation when we understand our
prophetic message we don't have to live
in the same kind of fear that everyone
else is living in because we know the
end of the story but if we're not
studying prophecy and I'm gonna tell you
something beloved the way many
Adventists are acting right now I don't
know if we have a full grasp of prophecy
because we're cheering for some things
that we should not be cheering for
beloved listen to me gotta understand
that we our faith is in the Word of God
and not promises that people mean so we
have a more sure word of prophecy that
allows us to lighten up because we know
what God says is gonna happen and if
we're not walking and if we're not
living by the Word of God if we're not
understanding the prophecies and what
God says it's coming we won't know how
to lighten up we'll just be walking in
darkness like so many other people
around us but of it it's time to lighten
up the Bible says but other times and
seasons 1st Thessalonians chapter 5
verse 1 but other times and seasons
brethren you have no need that I write
unto you for yourselves know perfectly
that the day of the Lord so cometh as a
thief in the night for when they shall
say peace and safety then sudden what
destruction comes up comes upon them as
travail upon a woman with child and they
shall not escape
you brethren are not in what darkness
that you should be or you should that
the day should overtake you as a thief
you are the children of what light and
the children of the day we are not of
the night nor of the darkness so what is
the light how do we light enough we
lighten up by understanding and
receiving salvation in Christ we lighten
up by receiving the Holy Spirit we
lighten up by understanding and reading
the Word of God and the spirit of
prophecy but there is more proverbs
chapter 6 verse 23 proverbs chapter 6
verse 23 3 the Bible says for the
commandment is a Watts lamp and the law
is light and reproof of instructions are
the way of life the Bible says that when
we keep the commandments we are
lightening up how many of you want to
lighten up
but look law is fulfilled in one word
and that word is love how do you lighten
up
love love many of us cannot lighten up
because we don't know how to love and in
fact the Bible says in first John 2:10
he that loveth his brother abideth in
the light and there is no occasion of
stumbling in him you want to lighten up
how many of you want to lighten up love
your brother I don't mean your blood
brother you're like oh that's easy I
love well it's not so easy but I love
them anyway no no we're not talking
about your blood brother we're not even
talking about your blood relative we're
not even talking about your friends love
your brother pray for those who use you
despitefully you want to lighten up you
got to learn how to love reason many of
us can't lighten up reason that light
cannot fall upon us it's powerful
because in the writings of spirit of
prophecy she says at the end of time I
saw
people going forth and their faces were
lighted up with the glory of God but
that cannot be us if we don't know how
to love that cannot be us if we're not
understanding the time we're living in
that cannot be yes if salvation is not
within us that cannot be us if the Holy
Spirit is not dwelling in us what I'm
trying to tell you church is that we
need to lighten up we need to learn how
to love the Bible says in Matthew 24:12
because iniquity shall abound the love
of many shall do watts max cold
we can't lighten up because we don't
know how to love our love has waxed cold
there's a fifth way to help you lighten
up Matthew chapter 5 verse 14 Matthew
chapter 5 verse 14 jesus said there you
are the light of the world a city that
is set on the hill cannot be he neither
do men light a candle and put it under a
bushel but on a candlestick that it may
give light unto all that are in the
house let your light so shine before men
that they may see your what good works
and glorify your father which is in
heaven
you like be nice lighten up
being nice I think about it how can I
help my neighbor you know that parable
of the Good Samaritan learn how to be a
good Samaritan that's how you can bring
light to a world that is in darkness let
your this little light of among us sing
it but you know I'm gonna let it shine
that's all God is asking he's just
saying guys just do me a favor
that's all I'm asking you to do just
lighten up and the way you do it is by
allowing my presence my spirit my power
to dwell in you the reason I want you to
lighten up is because this world is in
darkness
the sixth way to lighten up Daniel
chapter 12 verse three Daniel chapter 12
verse three the Bible says here Daniel
12 verse three and they that be wise
they that be one everyone why shall
shine as the brightness of the firmament
and they that turn many to what
righteousness as the stars for ever and
ever do you realize that when you win a
soul when you share the gospel with
others you are in essence lightening up
consciousness just lighten up guys why
are you so bogged down with the things
of this world lighten up and do what I
ask you to do we come the Church of
tired and mm-hmm Jesus I need you to go
out into the world and lighten up and
you can't lighten up because you got so
much going on which leads to that
seventh principle of lighting up Hebrews
chapter 12 verse 1 Hebrews chapter 12
verse 1 the Bible says wherefore seeing
we also are compassed about with so
great a cloud of witnesses let us lay
aside every one every wait what does
wait do it holds you down it holds you
down God needs you God needs you to lose
weight
yeah he needs you to lose weight you
need you to go on a weight-loss program
yes because many of us are carrying a
want around weight
and because we're carrying around weight
we don't know how to lighten up so you
can't go into all the world if you're
walking around with a whole lot of
weight and what is that weight
it's the cares of this world you know I
would I would share my faith and I would
do this but man I'm bogged down with
with my financial situation and but I
listen to me if there's any put the Bay
Area has the strongest gravitational
pull for weights I think in the world
maybe not in the world maybe in America
cost of living I mean you just name it
like there's a lot to weigh you down
here yet God says I need you to lose the
weight I need you to lose the weight I
need you to lighten up why because you
cannot go the places I want you to go
why because you're weighed down with the
cares of this world not only are many of
us weigh down with the cares of this
world many of us are overweight with
other people's sins other people's sins
against us
do you understand what I'm saying maybe
you don't so someone you you're carrying
around someone else's weight someone
else's sin she did this to me
two years ago and he did that to me 15
years ago and he did this to me
yesterday and all you're doing is
carrying around excess weight because we
don't know how to forgive
you and you do understand that right
when you are not forgiving you are
carrying around somebody else's weight
you have taken that upon yourself so you
are burdened down with an unforgiving
spirit and when you're burdened down it
is impossible for you to lighten up you
cannot do the two at the same time
guys
lighten up that's all I want to say to
you today guys
relax in the Lord and lighten up if you
would just do that we would be a healing
balm to a world in darkness Terry where
are you I'm gonna invites Harry to come
and to lead us in prayer and the pray
lord help me to drop my burdens help me
get on your weight loss program man
that's a sermon I'm gonna preach so that
would ya well that one's coming okay
God's weight loss program but Lord lead
us teach us how to lighten up I want to
invite you to kneel with us
precious father Lord we come before your
throne of grace today God and Lord you
know we can be quite an uptight Bunch we
need you today Lord father we thank you
that your son has said all power in
heaven and earth have been given unto me
and Lord we thank you that we've been
raised up to sit together with him in
heavenly places far above all
principality power might and Dominion
and every name that is named no matter
what that name is no matter what that
trial is no matter what that weight is
that struggle is God we thank you that
we have victory in Jesus today and
because of that awareness because of
that knowledge because your word God
cannot line cannot return to your void
God we think he that we can just lighten
up today Lord God and be a light to this
world or God help us Oh God father your
word says if we were troubled on all
sides you'd not distress four-plex not
in despair persecuted but not forsaken
cast down but not utterly destroyed
always bearing about in the body the
dying of the Lord Jesus so the life also
of Jesus might be made manifest in us
that's what our world needs to see today
God nobody wants to be drawn to to
somebody that's all uptight Lord God
will be drawn to smite if it's all
grumpy and grouchy and just over beard
and worn down we've got every reason to
celebrate we've got every reason to
shine we've got every reason Lord to be
joyous we thank you for but you brought
us through a lot of us sitting here
today knowing you Lord you brought us
through some stuff
brought us through some mess thank you
Jesus that you're still the same
yesterday today and forever God you're
still healing still working miracles
Lord God still shining Lord we give you
the glory thank you Lord for being that
light in us break these vessels Lord God
move this flesh out of the way move the
selfishness out of the way and Lord
don't let us respond in fear you said
perfect love had no fear Lord you love
we love you because you first loved us
so we thank you for that gun you've
given us heavens best in your son Jesus
Christ and so in the midst of
coronavirus and the midst of upheaval
hidden war and rumors looking worn
political upheaval and the midst of it
all God we are looking for a kingdom in
a city Lord whose builder is God we're
looking for something to come Lord we've
got something greater than this world
has to offer we just give you the glory
and the honor and the praise Lord God
for every brother and sister for every
child of God is sitting here today woke
up with one ounce of fear in their heart
many casts all their cares upon you
today in Jesus name Lord we give you the
glory and we give the praise thank you
Lord for welcoming us into this great
and awesome
Evon faith bond that is represented to
the world in Jesus name